Guide to the Boswell Collection Addition
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Estate Papers, 1774-1881; Series II; 1.0' linear feet (2 boxes)
  - OCHILTREE ESTATE
    - Estate Papers
      - Rental offers for farms in Ochiltree, 1829-65 (Box 14, Folder 406)
      - Receipts for John Douglas Boswell as factor, 1833 (Box 14, Folder 407)
      - Unidentified, 1836, 1865 (Box 14, Folder 408)
    - Factory Administration
      - Account sheets and receipts for rentals and interest due, 1822-32, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 409)
      - "Advertisement of Ochiltree Estate", 1834 Aug 2
        See: Oversize, Box 28, folder 794
      - Accounts and amended accounts of the intromissions of John Douglas Boswell, 1835 (Box 14, Folder 410)
      - Accounts and amended accounts of the intromissions of John Douglas Boswell, 1838 (Box 14, Folder 411)
      - Report of the intromissions of John Douglas Boswell, 1841 feb 9 (Box 14, Folder 412)
    - Feus and Cess
      - Accounts of the rentals of feus and cess, 1822-30 (Box 14, Folder 413-419)
      - Receipts for the rentals of feus and cess, 1822-32 (Box 14, Folder 420)
      - "Rental of Ochiltree Feus with Terms and Conditions of Tacks"
        See: Oversize, Box 28, folders 794-95
    - Land Records
      - Broomholm and Barnsdale, 1849 (Box 15, Folder 421)
      - Cawhillan, 1820-45 (Box 15, Folder 422)
      - Changue, 1836, 1848 (Box 15, Folder 423)
      - Changue and Garallan, 1822-37 (Box 15, Folder 424)
      - Changue and others, 1809, 1812 (Box 15, Folder 425)
      - Croslet, 1824 (Box 15, Folder 426)
      - Douglaston in Changue, 1859 (Box 15, Folder 427)
      - Garallan Smithy
        - Agreement between Patrick Douglas and Thomas McCormick for a new house, 1814 (Box 15, Folder 428)
        - Lease, 1854 (Box 15, Folder 429)
      - Humestone, 1837 (Box 15, Folder 430)
      - Mauchline Parish
        - Renunciation of Corslet, 1823 Nov 12 (Box 15, Folder 431)
        - Memorial for the Heritors of the Parish of Mauchline for the opinion of counsel, 1826 (Box 15, Folder 432)
      - Pennymore, 1813-35 (Box 15, Folder 433)
      - Slatehole, 1793-1834, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 434-435)
      - Steelpark, 1833 (Box 15, Folder 436)
      - Williams' West, 1833 (Box 15, Folder 437)
      - Willockshill, 1828-34 (Box 15, Folder 438)
- Land Records: Douglas of Garallan, 1634-1864; Series III; 1.0' linear feet (3 boxes)
  Series III, Land records: Douglas of Garallan is organized alphabetically by name of land and then chronologically within them. Where the full date of documents is not known, an effort has been made to approximate their probable order, but no specific circa dates have been assigned. The extensive material on the title to Schang has been organized in two sections: Inventories of the writs, and Progress of the writs, also chronologically arranged.
  - BOIG (SOUTH BOIG)
    - Tack of South Boig and parts of Boig for Mary Samson by Hugh Douglas, 1764 Mar 13 (Box 16, Folder 439)
    - Tack of South Boig by Patrick Douglas for John Cubbison, 1781 (Box 16, Folder 440)
    - Receipt by Patrick Douglas for Alexander Pagan on the account of John Cubbison, 1791 Jul 6 (Box 16, Folder 441)
    - Sasine and confirmation for Margery Cubbison, 1810 Feb 20 (Box 16, Folder 442)
    - Petition by Patrick Douglas against John Cubbison to the Sheriff, 1817 Jun 16 (Box 16, Folder 443)
      With: ALS from Hamilton Douglas Boswell to Patrick Douglas, 1817 Jun 7
    - "Sketch of the Lands of South Boag [Boig] lying in the Parish of New Cummock", 1817 Aug 2
      See: Oversize, Box 28, folder 796
    - Information concerning the progress of the writs of Garallan, 1821
      See: Oversize, Box 28, folder 797
    - Announcement of a roup of colliery machinery, printed handbill, 1822 Oct 22 (Box 16, Folder 444)
    - Information concerning the rights and valuations of Boig lands, 1822, 1823 (Box 16, Folder 445)
    - Information concerning the valuation of Boig lands as part of Cummock, 1830 Aug (Box 16, Folder 446)
    - Report by Neil Robson, Civil & Mining engineer, Glasgow, of a Survey of the Projected Mineral Railway..., printed, 1842 (Box 16, Folder 447)
    - Section of Strata near New Cumnock Commencing at the Gas Coal, n.d.
      See: Oversize, Box 28, folder 798
    - Tack of the minerals in Boig, 1845 (Box 16, Folder 448)
    - Leases and receipts for the coal at South Boig, 1850-64 (Box 16, Folder 449-450)
    - Lease of ground for a railway, 1853 (Box 16, Folder 451)
    - Report and valuation of the minerals on the land of South Boig, 1862 (Box 16, Folder 452)
    - Leases and receipts, 1863-64 (Box 16, Folder 453)
  - CUMMOCK PARISH
    - Copies of sasine registrations for lands of Torringzeane (Cummock dispute) (Box 16, Folder 454)
    - Valuation of the parish of Cummock in 1705 and 1759 (Box 16, Folder 455)
    - Valuation of the stock and teinds of the lands within the Parish of Cummock
      See: Oversize, Box 28, folder 799
    - Scheme of the proven rental of the parish of Old Cummock, n.d.
      See: Oversize, Box 29, folder 800
  - GARALLAN
    - Tack by Hugh Douglas for Andrew Crawford, 1720 Jan 3 (Box 16, Folder 456)
    - Discharge and resignation by Alexander Kennedy to Hugh Douglas, 1722 Jan 4 (Box 16, Folder 457)
    - Heritable bond by Hugh Douglas for William Campbell, 1722 May 30 (Box 16, Folder 458)
  - GEORGE SQUARE HOUSE, GLASGOW
    - Receipt by Robert Smith, architect in Glasgow, 1799 Jun 10 (Box 16, Folder 459)
    - Petition of John Wright to the Dean of Guild of Glasgow concerning intentions to build in George Square, 1812 May (Box 16, Folder 460)
    - Inventories of title deeds, 1863, 1864 (Box 16, Folder 462)
    - Offer of purchase, 1864 Mar 10 (Box 16, Folder 461)
    - Notes on objections to title and memorandum on searches, 1864 Jun (Box 16, Folder 463)
    - Plan of house, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 464)
  - NEWTOWN STREET PROPERTY (RAESIDE)
    - Disposition of feu rights to David Raeside, 1752 Nov 6 (Box 16, Folder 465)
    - Instrument of sasine for David Raeside, 1753 (Box 16, Folder 466)
    - Disposition to David Raeside, 1764 (Box 16, Folder 467)
    - Heritable bond by John Raeside to John Hogg, 1779 Apr 24 (Box 16, Folder 468)
    - General return as heir for John Raeside, 1779 Jul 15 (Box 16, Folder 469)
    - Bill from John Lindon to John Raeside, 1779 Aug 23 (Box 16, Folder 470)
    - Inhibition against Raeside, 1780 Mar 18 (Box 16, Folder 471)
    - Wadset disposition and instrument of sasine from John Raeside to David Watson, 1780 Mar (Box 16, Folder 472)
    - Registration of bill and execution of arrestment by John Lindon on John Raeside, 1780 Mar (Box 16, Folder 473)
    - Heritable bond by John Raeside to John Lindon, 1780 Jul 27 (Box 16, Folder 474)
    - Instrument of sasine in favor of John Lindon, 1780 Jul 27 (Box 16, Folder 475)
    - Instrument of sasine in favor of John Raeside, 1781 Feb (Box 16, Folder 476)
    - Instrument of sasine in favor of John Hogg by John Raeside, 1781 Mar 30 (Box 16, Folder 477)
    - Precept of clare constat by the magistrates of Newtown in favor of John Raeside, 1781 Oct 11 (Box 17, Folder 478)
    - Disposition and assignation by John Lindon to David Watson and John Hogg, 1782 (Box 17, Folder 479)
    - Disposition and assignation by John Hogg to David Watson, 1783 Jul 7 (Box 17, Folder 480)
    - Instrument of sasine in favor of David Watson, 1784 Apr 17 (Box 17, Folder 481)
    - Disposition and assignation by David Watson to John Ballantine, 1785 Aug 18 (Box 17, Folder 482)
    - Letters of agreement by David Watson concerning the sale of the Newtown properties, 1790, 1791 (Box 17, Folder 483)
    - Disposition and assignation by David Watson to William Crawford, 1792 Aug 31 (Box 17, Folder 484)
      See also: Oversize, Box 29, folder 801
    - Disposition by William Crawford to Helen Crawford, 1792 Aug 31 (Box 17, Folder 485)
  - SCHANG
    - Inventories of the writs
      - Inventory of the writs, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 486)
      - Inventory of the writs [damaged], n.d. (Box 17, Folder 487)
      - Inventory of the papers in Hugh Douglas of Garallan vs. Adam Stillie of Schang, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 488)
    - Progress of the writs
      - Contract between John Campbell and Adam Stillie, 1634 (Box 17, Folder 489)
      - Discharge by James ? for Adam Stillie of Schang, 1655 Nov 28 (Box 17, Folder 490)
      - Action by George Douglas against John Campbell, 1667 (Box 17, Folder 491)
      - Obligation by George Dunbar to ? Harbert, 1668 (Box 17, Folder 492)
      - Obligation by Hugh Campbell to George Douglas, 1669 Jan 12 (Box 17, Folder 493)
      - Obligation by Hugh Dunbar to Robert Gladstane, 1671 Apr 15 (Box 17, Folder 494)
      - Inhibition in the case of Campbell against Dunbar, 1671 Apr 25 (Box 17, Folder 495)
      - Regrat obligation by John Stillie against Hugh Dunbar, 1677 May 3 (Box 17, Folder 496)
      - Discharge and assignation by David Shaw for Hugh Campbell and George Douglas, 1679 (Box 17, Folder 497)
      - Bond by Adam Stillie and Agnes Logan, 1691 Jun 1 (Box 17, Folder 498)
      - Precept upon the bond between George Campbell and Patrick Crauford, [1692?] (Box 17, Folder 499)
      - Bond between Adam Stillie and Joseph Crauford, 1692 Mar 17 (Box 17, Folder 500)
      - Factorie by Hugh Campbell for James Rodden, [1693?] (Box 17, Folder 501)
      - Bond between Adam Stillie and Andrew Mcmanus, 1696 (Box 17, Folder 502)
      - Bond by Adam Stillie to James Gardner, 1698 Feb 10 (Box 17, Folder 503)
      - Bond by Adam Stillie to Mungo Campbell of Netherplace, 1698 Feb 19 (Box 17, Folder 504)
      - Bond by James Riddoch and Adam Stillie to Mungo Campbell of Netherplace, 1698 Feb 19 (Box 17, Folder 505)
      - Regrat bond between Thomas Brown and Adam Stillie, 1698 Sep 29 (Box 17, Folder 506)
      - Horn and poind: Brown against Stillie, 1698 Sep 30 (Box 17, Folder 507)
      - Precept bond by Ferguson against Adam Stillie, 1698 Oct 1 (Box 17, Folder 508)
      - Horn and poind: Inglis against Stillie, 1698 Oct 4 (Box 17, Folder 509)
      - Heritable bond by Adam Stillie to Thomas Brown, 1698 [Oct?] (Box 17, Folder 510)
      - Instrument of sasine by Adam Stillie in favor of Andrew McCowen, 1698 Nov 29 (Box 17, Folder 511)
      - Captione of Inglis against Stillie, 1699 (Box 17, Folder 512)
      - Precept of John Currie against Schang, 1699 Feb 2 (Box 17, Folder 513)
      - Heritable bond to Alexander Vallance, 1699 (Box 17, Folder 514)
      - Instrument of sasine in Schang for Alexander Vallance, 1699 (Box 17, Folder 515)
      - Decreet of poinding by Thomas Brown against Colville and Schang, 1699 Nov 24 (Box 17, Folder 516)
      - Precept of poinding by Sir George Campbell against Colville and Stillie of Schang, 1699 Nov 24 (Box 17, Folder 517)
      - Assignation of a debt against Adam Stillie, 1700 Jan 1 (Box 17, Folder 518)
      - Assignation by Thomas Brown to Marie Farquhar, 1700 (Box 17, Folder 519)
      - Assignation by William Logan to Hugh Dunbar, [1702?] (Box 17, Folder 520)
      - Translation by Marie Farquhar to Mungo Campbell of Netherplace, 1704 Dec? (Box 17, Folder 521)
      - Decreet suspending the letter and absolution: Hugh Douglas against Adam Stillie, 1705 Feb 19 (Box 17, Folder 522)
      - Obligation by Adam Stillie to John Reid, 1705 Jul 15 (Box 17, Folder 523)
      - Regrat bond by Thomas Brown against Adam Stillie, 1705 Aug 28 (Box 17, Folder 524)
      - "Account anent Schangs Adjudication", 1705 (Box 17, Folder 525)
      - Letter from William Logan to Mungo Campbell of Netherplace concerning adjudication of Schang, 1722 Jan 6 (Box 17, Folder 526)
      - Discharge of feu duties for Mungo Campbell of Netherplace, 1737 Oct 31 (Box 17, Folder 527)
      - Unidentified, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 528)
- Financial Papers, 1770-1877; Series IV; 2.0' linear feet (6 boxes)
  Series IV, Financial Papers, is organized into two subseries: Boswell of Auchinleck Family and Douglas of Garallan Family. Material is arranged first chronologically, by family generation, and therein alphabetically by subject or category of material. Beyond that, under subject or category, the files are arranged chronologically.
  - BOSWELL OF AUCHINLECK
    - Boswell, Sir Alexander
      - Heritable bond by Sir Alexander Boswell to William Roxburgh and Alexander Boswell, W. S., 1812 Dec 9 (Box 18, Folder 529)
      - Instrument of sasine in security for Dr. William Roxburgh over the lands of Knockroon, 1813 Jan 19 (Box 18, Folder 530)
      - Decreet Arbitral between Sir Alexander Boswell and his brother and sisters, 1805 Feb 7 (Box 18, Folder 531)
      - Estate of Sir Alexander Boswell
        - Accounts and memoranda concerning the heritable estate, 1822-31, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 532-535)
        - Accounts of the creditors of the late Sir Alexander Boswell, 1822-31 (Box 18, Folder 536-537)
        - Accounts of Alexander Hamilton, W. S., with the Executors-Creditors of the late Sir Alexander Boswell, 1822-29 (Box 18, Folder 538-540)
        - Inventories of the personal estate of the late Sir Alexander Boswell, 1823, 1824 (Box 18, Folder 541)
        - Accounts of the Executrix-creditor of the late Sir Alexander Boswell, 1824-38 (Box 18, Folder 542-544)
        - Charges against the Auchinleck estate by the Executrix-creditor, 1828-29 (Box 18, Folder 545)
        - Proposal to the Personal Creditors of the late Sir Alexander Boswell from Sir James Boswell, 1828 (Box 18, Folder 546)
          See also: Oversize, Box 29, folder 802
        - Receipts for the Executrix-creditor of the late Sir Alexander Boswell, 1833-39 (Box 18, Folder 547-551)
        - Lists of the personal creditors of the late Sir Alexander Boswell (Box 18, Folder 552)
      - Insurance
        - Life insurance policy of Sir Alexander Boswell, 1819 Jul 2
          See: Bsd, folder 803
        - Assignation of policy to Hamilton Douglas Boswell, 1821 Apr 30 (Box 18, Folder 553)
        - Assignation and bond on policy to Jane Crawford, 1821-22 (Box 18, Folder 554)
      - Progress of the settlement of the estate
        - Bills and claims submitted by the creditors of the late Sir Alexander Boswell, 1822-33 (Box 18, Folder 555-559)
        - Minutes of the meetings of the curators and creditors of Sir Alexander Boswell, 1822-24 (Box 19, Folder 560-562)
        - Notices to the personal creditors of Sir Alexander Boswell, 1822-27 (Box 19, Folder 563)
        - Memorial and queries for Sir James Boswell of Auchinleck, Baronet, and for the tutors and creditors, 1823 Apr (Box 19, Folder 564)
        - Remarks upon the memorial, 1823 [Apr] (Box 19, Folder 565)
        - Report by the Committee of Creditors of Sir Alexander Boswell for the general meeting of creditors, 1823 May 6 (Box 19, Folder 566)
        - Statement of claims against the personal estate of the late Sir Alexander Boswell, 1823 Oct 15 (Box 19, Folder 567)
        - Memorial and report concerning claim, 1823 Dec 26 (Box 19, Folder 568)
        - Copy obligation to be signed by the heritable creditors, [1823?] (Box 19, Folder 569)
        - Memorial for Sir James Boswell to draw from the Insurance offices, 1824 Feb 5 (Box 19, Folder 570)
        - Draft of deed of agreement by Auchinleck creditors (unsigned), 1828 Aug (Box 19, Folder 571)
        - Minutes of a meeting of the Committee of Creditors, 1828 Sep 2 (Box 19, Folder 572)
        - Account of sums paid by Sir James Boswell in composition to the creditors of Sir Alexander Boswell, 1829 Oct (Box 19, Folder 573)
        - Arrestments for debts for Grizel Cuming Boswell, 1830 (Box 19, Folder 574)
        - Letters of general charge against Sir James Boswell, 1831 Jan-Nov (Box 19, Folder 575)
        - Summons of constitution for Sir James Boswell, 1831 Nov (Box 19, Folder 576)
        - Summons of consititution for Sir James Boswell, 1831 Nov (Box 19, Folder 577)
        - Summons wrappers, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 578)
        - Summons of consititution for Sir James Boswell (various creditors, incl. William Roxburgh), 1831-32 (Box 19, Folder 579)
        - State of claim by Sir William Forbes on the entailed estate, 1832 Oct 22 (Box 19, Folder 580)
        - Decreet cognitionis causa tantum for the Roxburgh creditors against Sir James Boswell, 1833 Feb 1 (Box 19, Folder 581)
        - Memorandum of valuation on Ochiltree, 1833 Apr 26 (Box 19, Folder 582)
        - Description of the lands in the summons of ranking and sale of Ochiltree lands, (Stirling against Boswell creditors), 1833 (Box 19, Folder 583)
        - Report of Act and Commission in process of ranking and sale, 1833 May 15 (Box 20, Folder 584)
        - Memorandum by the Common Agent in the Ranking and Sale, 1833 Dec 16 (Box 20, Folder 585)
        - Bond of caution for John Douglas Boswell as factor of Ochiltree, 1833 Dec 26 (Box 20, Folder 586)
        - Petition for sequestration in the Stirling process of ranking and sale, with report by the Common Agent, 1834 Jan (Box 20, Folder 587)
        - Memorial and abstract in ranking and sale, Stirling vs. the Creditors of Sir Alexander Boswell, printed court documents, 1834 Jun 24 (Box 20, Folder 588)
        - Observations on the advertisement of the Ochiltree ranking and sale, 1834 Aug 5 (Box 20, Folder 589)
        - Process of multiplepoinding raised by Matthew Montgomerie, 1834 (Box 20, Folder 590)
        - Specification of writings to be recovered...in the process of multiplepoinding, 1834-36, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 591-593)
        - State of interest due on debts secured on the Ochiltree estate, 1835
          See: Oversize, Box 29, folder 804
        - Rental on Ochiltree lands unsold in the Stirling sale, 1835
          See: Bsd, folder 805
        - Reclaiming note for Sir James Boswell in the process of multiplepoinding, printed court document, 1836 Jan 12 (Box 20, Folder 594)
        - Petition of Sir James Boswell to excamb entailed lands, printed court document, 1837 Jan 26 (Box 20, Folder 595)
        - Report on the petition to excamb, printed court document, 1837 Dec 6 (Box 20, Folder 596)
        - Summons: Matthew Mongomerie against Mrs. Jane Douglas Boswell in the process of multiplepoinding, 1839 Mar 23 (Box 20, Folder 597)
        - Specification of the writings to be recovered...in the process of multiplepoinding, 1841 (Box 20, Folder 598)
        - Decree of exoneration for the judicial factor of Ochiltree, 1841 Feb 27 (Box 20, Folder 599)
        - Chancery documents attesting to baptisms and burials in the family of Sir James Boswell, 1842 Sep (Box 20, Folder 600)
        - Factory by Sir James Boswell in favor of John Douglas Boswell, 1848 Feb 5 (Box 20, Folder 601)
        - Interim decree and act of warrant for payment in the process of multiplepoinding, 1854 Jul 4 (Box 20, Folder 602)
        - Receipts by Sir James Boswell for John Douglas Boswell, 1856, 1857 (Box 20, Folder 603)
        - Assignation by the Executors creditors of Sir Alexander Boswell in favor or James Dalgleish of Ardnamurchan, 1866 Nov (Box 21, Folder 604)
        - Obligation and declaration by Sir Thomas Cunninghame in favor of the Executors creditors, 1866 Dec (Box 21, Folder 605)
        - Obligation and declaration by Mrs. Vassall and husband in favor of the Executors creditors, 1867 Mar 16 (Box 21, Folder 606)
        - Assignation by the Executors creditors in favor of Mrs. Margaret Amelia Vassall, 1867 Mar 18 (Box 21, Folder 607)
        - Discharge to the Executors creditors of the late Sir Alexander Boswell, 1867 Jul 6 (Box 21, Folder 608)
        - Report and discharge by the Executrix of Sir Thomas Cuninghame in favor of the Executors creditors, 1872 Jul 30 (Box 21, Folder 609)
        - Report on accounts between the Executors of the late Matthew Montgomerie and the Executors, 1874 Dec 3 (Box 21, Folder 610)
        - State of the Intromissions and Final scheme of division of the funds, 1876 May
          See: Oversize, Box 29, folder 806
        - Discharge by the creditors to the Executors creditors of Sir Alexander Boswell, 1876 Dec 6 (Box 21, Folder 611)
        - Account-current of the Executors creditors of Sir Alexander Boswell, 1877 Oct 2 (Box 21, Folder 612)
        - Inventory of writings sent to the agents for the Executors creditors, 1877 [Oct?] (Box 21, Folder 613)
        - Notice of shipment of accounts and inventory, 1877 Oct 2 (Box 21, Folder 614)
    - Boswell, James, the younger
      - "Administration of the goods...left unadministered...", 1834 Apr 23
        See: Oversize, Box 29, folder 807
      - Reports on the suit of Jacks v. How and others, 1834-35 (Box 21, Folder 615)
      - Account of Administrators' intromissions with the estate, 1835 (Box 21, Folder 616)
  - DOUGLAS OF GARALLAN
    - Douglas, Charles
      - Indenture of Crawford Cochrane as overseer for Fairlie Christie, 1775 Dec 7 (Box 21, Folder 617)
      - Indenture of John Bell as overseer for Charles Douglas, 1790 Jan 7 (Box 21, Folder 618)
      - Power of attorney from Charles Douglas to Patrick Douglas, 1813 Jul 28
        See: Oversize, Box 29, folder 808
      - Power of attorney from Charles Douglas to Patrick Douglas, 1814 Mar 10
        See: Oversize, Box 29, folder 809
      - Shipping receipt for goods for Charles Douglas, 1815 Mar 22 (Box 21, Folder 619)
      - Account between Charles Douglas and Hamilton Douglas Boswell, 1815 (Box 21, Folder 620)
      - Inventories of the estate of Charles Douglas, with copies of his will, 1815-16 (Box 21, Folder 621)
      - Power of attorney from Jane Douglas Boswell to Robert Hamilton and John Steel, 1816 Mar 2 (Box 21, Folder 622)
      - "Memorandum for Mr. Patterson" concerning a proposed settlement, 1821 Jun-Jul (Box 21, Folder 623)
    - Douglas, Patrick
      - Bell inheritance
        - Will of Alexander Bell of Jamaica, 1778 Mar 9 (Box 21, Folder 624)
        - Petition of Alexander Bell to the Commissary of Glasgow, 1778 May 13 (Box 21, Folder 625)
        - Account between Alexander Bell and Patrick Douglas, 1777-78 (Box 21, Folder 626)
      - Douglas, Heron & Co. bankruptcy
        - List of the Proprietors of Stock in the Banking Society, under the Firm of Mess. Douglas, Heron, & Co.: Edinburgh, 1770 (Box 22, Folder 627)
        - Bills and receipts, 1772-90 (Box 22, Folder 628)
        - Account correspondence from George Home to Patrick Douglas, 1776-92 (Box 22, Folder 629-631)
          Includes some printed circular letters signed by Home
        - Circular letter, signed "A Partner," warning against the committee's plan to bring actions against partners, [1779?]
          See: Oversize, Box 29, folder 810
        - Circular letters (some printed), 1779-80 (Box 22, Folder 632)
        - Lists of debts of Douglas, Heron & Co. to be sold at roup, 1788-1805
          See: Oversize, Box 29, folder 811
        - Minutes of a meeting of the partners of Douglas, Heron & Co., 1793
          See: Oversize, Box 29, folder 812
        - Balance sheet for Douglas, Heron & Co., 1804
          See: Oversize, Box 29, folder 813
        - Conveyance by George Home for Patrick Douglas, 1807 Feb 10 (Box 22, Folder 633)
        - Authorization of agent to Douglas, Heron & Co. by Jane Douglas Boswell, 1828 Feb 11 (Box 22, Folder 634)
        - Ratification and discharge by Douglas, Heron & Co., 1828 Mar 4 (Box 22, Folder 635)
        - Process of Gilbert McAdam's debt to Douglas, Heron & Co. as claimed by Jane Douglas Boswell, 1776-1839 (Box 22, Folder 636-641)
      - Personal debt to James McWhirter and his trustees, 1776-81 (Box 22, Folder 642-644)
      - Personal debt to Robert Naismith, 1787-92 (Box 22, Folder 645-646)
      - Personal estate of Patrick Douglas: inventories, 1822 (Box 22, Folder 647)
      - Personal estate of Patrick Douglas: Stamp Office records, 1822 (Box 22, Folder 648)
    - Boswell, Hamilton Douglas
      - Personal estate
        - Memoranda, 1822-25 (Box 23, Folder 649)